const e="commerce",a=200,t=48,i=[{id:149,question:"Consumers require protection against exploitation to ensure ",option:{a:"adequate consumer awareness",b:"availability of product variety",c:"the sale of quality products",d:"increased aggregate demand."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:150,question:"The business environment that takes into cognizance the age distribution, ethnic mix and educational level of the consumer is",option:{a:"demographic environment",b:"economic environment",c:"cultural environment",d:"natural environment."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:151,question:"An agent who takes title to goods and has authority  to buy and sell on behalf of another is",option:{a:"a jobber   ",b:"a broker  ",c:"a factor",d:"an auctioneer."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:152,question:"Citizens are against privatisation mainly because of ",option:{a:"the rationalization of organizations",b:"increased prices of goods and services",c:"the likelihood of monopoly",d:"ineffective management."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:153,question:"The major achievement of ECOWAS is",option:{a:"the expansion of regional trade",b:"the emergence of a monetary union",c:"infrastructure! development in member countries",d:"mobility of labour among member countries."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:154,question:"An announcement of a person's willingness to enter into a contract is referred to as ",option:{a:"a proxy",b:"an offer ",c:"a consideration ",d:"an acceptance."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:155,question:"The macro-environmental forces and trends which are a constraint on business operations are  referred to as  ",option:{a:"technological factors",b:"economic factors   ",c:"external factors ",d:"internal factors."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:156,question:"Which of the following best describes inputs for any production activity?   ",option:{a:"Natural resources.",b:" Business resources.",c:"Human resources.",d:"Material resources."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:157,question:"Personal selling is most effective in marketing industrial goods because it involves",option:{a:"recognition and attachment to customers",b:"personal interaction and information gathering",c:"demonstrations and product acceptability",d:"after-sales services and product demonstrations."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:158,question:"The controllable variables that a firm uses to achieve its marketing objectives are called",option:{a:"marketing principles ",b:"marketing mix",c:"marketing concepts",d:"marketing functions."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:159,question:"Public relations and advertising are similar in terms of",option:{a:"communicating product information",b:"customer education ",c:"the mode of operation",d:"creating a favourable attitude."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:160,question:"A major function of an entrepreneur is",option:{a:"decision-making ",b:"encouraging competition",c:"human-resource training",d:"motivating employees."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:161,question:"A Memorandum of Association is applicable to a",option:{a:" sole trader ",b:"joint-stock company",c:" partnership   ",d:" public corporation."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:162,question:"The sustainable growth of commerce is largely due to ",option:{a:"marketing   ",b:"advertising",c:"exchange ",d:"branding."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:163,question:"A major advantage of a cooperative society is that it ",option:{a:"gives members the opportunity to unite",b:"draws members closer to government",c:"promotes awareness among members",d:"encourages thrift among members."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:164,question:"The making of doors from timber planks is a type of ",option:{a:"manufacturing ",b:"tertiary production",c:"secondary production   ",d:"primary production."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:165,question:"Law-making is an example of ",option:{a:"indirect service",b:"commercial occupation ",c:"direct service",d:"industrial occupation."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:166,question:"A document which advertises the shares of a company is known as a  ",option:{a:"memorandum of satisfaction   ",b:"dividend warrant     ",c:"deed",d:"prospectus."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:167,question:"The scope of economic activities can be enlarged by    ",option:{a:"transportation and trading   ",b:"business and its promotion  ",c:"trading and aids to trade",d:"insurance and banking."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:168,question:"The creation of utilities to satisfy human wants is referred to as   ",option:{a:"production  ",b:"consumption",c:"industrialization    ",d:"occupation."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:169,question:"A major criticism of a cooperative society is",option:{a:"limited capital ",b:"granting excessive loans to members   ",c:"selling goods on credit to non- members    ",d:"management incompetence."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:170,question:"An economic activity which deals with natural resources is a form of  ",option:{a:"extraction",b:"refining   ",c:"construction ",d:"manufacturing."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:171,question:"The first stage in tourism planning is",option:{a:"assessing feedback from tourists",b:"preparing a list of tourist attractions",c:"creating recreational opportunities",d:"building community support."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:172,question:"An agreement by the insurer to compensate the insured for losses suffered is   ",option:{a:"policy",b:"surrender value   ",c:"caveat emptor ",d:"indemnity."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:173,question:"One of the functions of the Nigeria Ports Authority is the provision of  ",option:{a:"facilities to enhance the speedy loading and offloading of ",b:"facilities to ensure that goods get to their destinations  ",c:"shelter for operators of cargoes",d:" courier services to ensure speedy delivery."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:174,question:"The   World   Tourism   Organization   has   its headquarters in ",option:{a:"New York    ",b:"Paris",c:"Madrid     ",d:"London."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:175,question:"Digital computer is divided into ",option:{a:"analogue, hybrid and mini ",b:"super, mainframe, mini and micro    ",c:"mainframe, hybrid and micro",d:"super, mainframe, micro and analogue."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:176,question:"A distinctive advantage of GSM is its ",option:{a:"mobility",b:" cost   ",c:"stability   ",d:"coverage."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:177,question:"In the permanent storage device, DASD means",option:{a:"Data Access Storage Device",b:"Data Access Systems Device",c:"Direct Access Systems Device",d:"Direct Access Storage Device."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:178,question:"The major determinant of fire insurance premium is the ",option:{a:"type and structure of the property to be insured ",b:"usefulness of the property to the owner",c:"owner of the property to be insured",d:"extent of fire damage anticipated."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:179,question:"The Internet is a system of telecommunications used for   ",option:{a:"communicating long-distance messages ",b:"sending and receiving text messages",c:"sending electronic messages .",d:"communicating messages through telegrams."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:180,question:"A written  agreement for  hiring  a  ship for transporting goods is a ",option:{a:"consular invoice",b:"bill of lading ",c:"charter party ",d:"certificate of origin."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:181,question:"The major function of a trade association is that it",option:{a:"liaises with foreign trade associations",b:"helps to promote foreign trade",c:"facilitates members' access to credit facilities",d:"helps to promote research on behalf of members."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:182,question:"A major setback of international trade is",option:{a:"inadequate exports",b:"economic sanctions",c:"devaluation of currency",d:"exchange rate appreciation."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:183,question:"Which of the following requires payment into the payee's account?   ",option:{a:"Crossed cheque.",b:"Travellerâ€™s cheque.    ",c:" Open cheque.",d:"Certified cheque."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:184,question:"The traditional way of paying cooperative dividend is to distribute profit in proportion to members'",option:{a:"subscriptions  ",b:"total savings",c:"volume of purchases   ",d:"contributions."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:185,question:"The abbreviation C & F indicates that the",option:{a:"production cost excludes the cost of carriage",b:"selling price includes the cost of carriage",c:"cost of production includes delivery charges",d:"cost price includes the cost of carriage."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:186,question:"The sale of foreign investment and gold reserves can be used to ",option:{a:"correct adverse balance of trade",b:"increase invisible imports",c:"correct adverse balance of payments",d:"correct a budget deficit."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:187,question:"A share premium is an example of",option:{a:"issued capital ",b:"capital stock ",c:"equity capital",d:"capital reserve."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:188,question:"A major benefit a debtor can derive from using a credit facility is ",option:{a:"better service  ",b:"goodwill",c:"convenience    ",d:"control."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:189,question:"The function  of money that facilitates the comparison of the quality of goods as a basis of exchange is the   ",option:{a:"unit of account",b:"measure of value ",c:"store of value",d:"medium of exchange"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:190,question:"The difference between the buying and selling price of shares is known as   ",option:{a:"brokerage",b:"margin   ",c:"jobber's turn   ",d:"gross profit."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:191,question:"Which of the following is a risk-free security?",option:{a:"Preference share.   ",b:"Ordinary share.",c:"Treasury bill.    ",d:"Debenture."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:192,question:"The central bank controls the quantity of money in circulation through  ",option:{a:"open-market operations",b:"decreasing the tax rate ",c:"issuing new currencies    ",d:"increasing the tax rate."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:193,question:"The selling of new shares to existing shareholders is referred to as ",option:{a:"public issue ",b:"offer for sale",c:"rights issue  ",d:"bonus issue."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:194,question:"A new company requiring a large amount of equity finance may source funds from the",option:{a:"capital market   ",b:"central bank",c:"money market    ",d:"commercial banks."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:195,question:"A credit instrument which also serves as a legal tender is   ",option:{a:"cheque    ",b:"paper money",c:"voucher   ",d:"money order."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:196,question:"The body regulating the sale and purchase of shares in Nigeria is the ",option:{a:" Corporate   Affairs Commission   ",b:"Securities   and   Exchange Commission    ",c:"Securities   and   Exchange Tribunal     ",d:"Nigerian Stock Exchange."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"}],o={subject:e,status:200,total:48,data:i};export{i as data,o as default,a as status,e as subject,t as total};
